There are very few people who do not use gas cylinders in their homes
.  In some situations,
accidents due to gas cylinders
occur.  If such accidents
occur, you
will get coverage of up to Rs 50 lakh.  But there are
some things
to note in this regard.
To get insurance, the expiration date of the cylinder will
be related to the date.  Every
cylinder will have an expiration date.   If an
accident occurs with a cylinder that has passed its expiration date, insurance
coverage will not be available.  Therefore, everyone should
pay special attention to the expiration date of the cylinder
.  Also, when taking out an LPG connection, it must
be taken in your own name.
Insurance
coverage is not available if a connection in someone else's name is used.  Only
the person who has registered the cylinder will
receive the insurance amount.
Also, there is no provision for appointing a nominee
.  Therefore, if
the person to whom the cylinder is registered
dies in an accident, a claim
cannot be made.  Petroleum companies like Indian Oil,
Hindustan Petroleum, and Bharat Petroleum
have this insurance policy.  They
provide this protection to customers and other assets through third-party crop insurance.  Insurance claims can be made for
property damage and death caused by accidents caused by gas cylinders
.  Currently,
this insurance with LPG connection is provided through ICICI Lombard
.  According to this, in case of an accident, a
maximum of Rs. 50 lakhs will be
available.  If death
occurs in an accident, you will get up to that lakh rupees.
Customers will
receive a maximum of Rs 40 lakh for property damage.  If an
accident due to a gas cylinder occurs, you
must apply for this within 30 days of the accident.  Once claimed, the
money will be received within three to five months.
You should understand more information related to this carefully before becoming a
part of this project.  If you contact the LPG
distributor further, you will be
able to understand the exact details about this scheme.